nelsonnet.com.au 2019-06-30

# PrivacyCentre | Cengage Australia

#### **About this Privacy Policy**

We understand and appreciate that privacy is a major concern for individuals who trust us with their personal and sensitive information, as it is for us. 

This policy details our commitment to the responsible and transparent use of private information. We commit to collecting, using, storing and disclosing this information in a lawful and responsible way. 

Please read this policy carefully to understand how we will treat your personal information.  It describes what you can do if you have any concerns or complaints about the way we collect or process personal information. 

We will act in accordance with the Commonwealth Privacy Act 1988, the New Zealand Privacy Act 1993 and, to the extent it is relevant, the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) 2016/679 that stipulate how organisations should manage the collection, use and disclosure of personal information.   

GDPR applies to Cengage Australia as Cengage have offices in the European Union. When processing your personal information, our lawful basis is:

  * Legitimate interest to fulfil any contractual agreements between you and us if you are an existing or prospective customer
  * Consent obtained prior to promoting our services to you

#### **What kinds of information do we collect?**

The Personal Information we collect is for the purposes of administering the terms of your service/s and conducting business transactions with you. This information includes (but is not limited to)

**Personal information** | **Use**  
---|---  
Name  | To create an account and, subsequently, verify your identity   
Email address  | To identify you on login to our applications and contact you (including for surveys, competitions or promotions)   
Address  | To send materials to you or communicate with you   
Phone number  | To call or send SMS messages   
Dare of birth/age  | To determine appropriate data retention rules to apply to your account   
Occupation  | To customise offers   
School affiliation  | To target materials accurately to your needs   
Area of study  | To provide you with information about new or existing products and services   
Grades  | To support your teacher's tuition   
Expected graduation date  | To ensure that you are complying with our terms and conditions   
Purchase history  | To support product queries   
Content use  | To determine time spent on materials and in-product assessments   
Credit card information  | To transfer to our third-party payment provider (this information is never stored by us)   
Banking information  | To process royalty payments   
  
#### **A special note about children**

We collect information about children in order to deliver a product or service. We do not market to children. Parents must consent to the collection and use of personal information for any child under the age of 18.

#### **How do we protect personal information?**

We are committed to protecting the security of your personal information and we take all reasonable precautions to protect it from unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. We will also take all reasonable steps to ensure vendors comply with secure handling of your personal information.

We employ website encryption on pages that contain personal information and encrypt personal data at rest.

We encourage the use of complex passwords (incorporating upper and lower case letters, at least eight characters, at least one special character and at least one number) to secure user accounts. 

#### **Notification of data breach**

In accordance with obligations under relevant data protection laws, we will inform the competent regulatory authority and affected individuals without undue delay in the event of a personal information data breach.  We will provide all relevant information relating to the data breach as part of our notification. We will use reasonable endeavours to assist you in mitigating the adverse effects of any data breach.

#### **How do we disclose personal information?**

We may disclose personal information to provide services to you (for example, we outsource mailing to a courier and will provide your personal information accordingly when you purchase material from us to send that material to you) and to advise you about our new or existing services.

We engage with third party applications including, but not limited to, ServiceNow, Google Analytics, Dynatrace and Splunk to provide customer support, website usage information, application performance and security monitoring functions. Some of these applications may contain personal information.

We may also disclose personal information when required by law.

#### **Do we transfer personal information to overseas recipients?**

We may transfer personal information to the United States, as necessary to provide services. In this instance we have standard contractual data protection clauses in place to protect your data.

#### **Rights of individuals**

**Right** | **Details**  
---|---  
Quality of information  | We will take reasonable steps to ensure the personal information we hold about you is accurate, up-to-date and complete.   
Access to personal information  | You can access the personal information we hold about you. Your personal information will usually be available within 14 business days of your request (subject to allowable exemptions). We will let you know if additional time is required.   
Rectifying personal information  | You have a right to ask us to correct any inaccurate personal information we hold about you. We will take reasonable steps to correct your personal information to ensure it is accurate, up-to-date, complete, relevant and not misleading.   
Erasing personal information  | Where one of the grounds specified in Article 17 of the GDPR applies, you have a right to ask us to erase any personal information we hold about you.  We will do that without undue delay.   
Right to withdraw consent  | Where applicable under GDPR, if we have collected and processed any personal information on the basis of your consent, then you can withdraw your consent at any time.  Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.   
Right to object and data portability  | Where applicable under GDPR, you can object to processing of your personal information, ask us to restrict processing of your personal information or request portability of your personal information to another provider.   
Right to object to automated profiling  | Where applicable under GDPR, you can object to decisions being taken based solely on automated means, including profiling, which produce legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affect you.   
Exercising rights  | You can exercise any of these rights by contacting us using the contact details provided below.  We may require evidence of your identity when processing your request to access, rectify, erase, port or cease profiling your personal information. We will process your request as soon as reasonably practicable, provided we are not otherwise prevented from doing so on legal grounds. If we are unable to meet your request, we will let you know why.   
  
* * *
